Guide to the Carlton E. Morse Papers, 1932-1982
Department of Special Collections
Carlton E. Morse Papers,
1932-1982
Special Collections M0362
Morse, Carlton E.
47 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Radio dramatist, joined production staff of NBC in 1930. Wrote One Man's Family, 1932-1959, I Love a Mystery, 1939-1944, and other programs.
Scope and Content
Summary: Radio and TV scripts, correspondence, newsclips, publicity materials, photographs, 90 reels of TV film, and sound recordings.
Container List
- Series 1. Bound Scripts, 164 Volumes
  - Subseries A. ONE MAN'S FAMILY: Radio Scripts
    - From April 29, 1932 to July 27, 1932 (Volume 1)
    - August 3, 1932 September 14, 1932 (Volume 2)
    - October 5, 1932 December 21, 1932 (Volume 3)
    - January 11, 1933 April 5, 1933 (Volume 4)
    - April 12, 1933 July 5, 1933 (Volume 5)
    - July 12, 1933 October 4, 1933 (Volume 6)
    - October 11, 1933 December 27, 1933 (Volume 7)
    - January 5, 1934 March 30, 1934 (Volume 8)
    - March 6, 1934 June 29, 1934 (Volume 9)
    - July 6, 1934 September 28, 1934 (Volume 10)
    - October 5, 1934 November 16, 1934 (Volume 11)
    - November 21, 1934 February 10, 1935 (Volume 12)
    - February 17, 1935 March 24, 1935 (Volume 13)
    - March 31, 1935 June 23, 1935 (Volume 14)
    - June 30, 1935 September 22, 1935 (Volume 15)
    - September 29, 1935 December 22, 1935 (Volume 16)
    - December 29, 1935 March 22, 1936 (Volume 17)
    - March 29, 1936 June 21, 1936 (Volume 18)
    - June 28, 1936 September 20, 1936 (Volume 19)
    - September 27, 1936 December 20, 1936 (Volume 20)
    - December 27, 1936 March 21, 1937 (Volume 21)
    - March 1, 1937 June 20, 1937 (Volume 22)
    - June 27, 1937 September 19, 1937 (Volume 23)
    - September 26, 1937 December 26, 1937 (Volume 24)
    - January 2, 1938 March 27, 1938 (Volume 25)
    - April 3, 1938 June 26, 1938 (Volume 26)
    - July 3, 1938 September 18, 1938 (Volume 27)
    - October 2, 1938 December 25, 1938 (Volume 28)
    - January 1, 1939 February 26, 1939 (Volume 29)
    - April 2, 1939 June 25, 1939 (Volume 30)
    - September 2, 1939 September 24, 1939 (Volume 31)
    - October 1, 1939 December 24, 1939 (Volume 32)
    - January 7, 1940 March 24, 1940 (Volume 33)
    - April 7, 1940 June 30, 1940 (Volume 34)
    - July 6, 1940 September 29, 1940 (Volume 35)
    - October 6, 1940 December 29, 1940 (Volume 36)
    - January 5, 1941 March 30, 1941 (Volume 37)
    - April 6, 1941 June 30, 1941 (Volume 38)
    - July 6, 1941 September 28, 1941 (Volume 39)
    - October 5, 1941 December 28, 1941 (Volume 40)
    - January 4, 1942 March 29, 1942 (Volume 41)
    - April 5, 1942 June 28, 1942 (Volume 42)
    - July 5, 1942 September 27, 1942 (Volume 43)
    - October 4, 1942 December 27, 1942 (Volume 44)
    - January 3, 1943 April 4, 1943 (Volume 45)
    - April 11, 1943 July 4, 1943 (Volume 46)
    - July 11, 1943 October 3, 1943 (Volume 47)
    - October 10, 1943 December 26, 1943 (Volume 48)
    - January 2, 1944 March 26, 1944 (Volume 49)
    - April 2, 1944 July 2, 1944 (Volume 50)
    - July 9, 1944 October 1, 1944 (Volume 51)
    - October 8, 1944 December 31, 1944 (Volume 52)
    - January 7, 1945 March 27, 1945 (Volume 53)
    - April 3, 1945 July 3, 1945 (Volume 54)
    - July 15, 1945 October 7, 1945 (Volume 55)
    - October 14, 1945 December 30, 1945 (Volume 56)
    - January 6, 1946 March 31, 1946 (Volume 57)
    - April 7, 1946 June 30, 1946 (Volume 58)
    - July 7, 1946 September 29, 1946 (Volume 59)
    - October 6, 1946 December 39, 1946 (Volume 60)
    - January 5, 1947 March 30, 1947 (Volume 61)
    - April 6, 1947 June 29, 1947 (Volume 62)
    - July 6, 1947 September 21, 1947 (Volume 63)
    - September 28, 1947 December 28, 1947 (Volume 64)
    - January 4, 1948 March 28, 1948 (Volume 65)
    - April 4, 1948 June 27, 1948 (Volume 66)
    - July 4, 1948 September 26, 1948 (Volume 67)
    - October 3, 1948 December 26, 1948 (Volume 68)
    - January 2, 1949 March 27, 1949 (Volume 69)
    - April 30, 1949 July 3, 1949 (Volume 70)
    - July 4, 1949 September 26, 1949 (Volume 71)
  - Subseries B. ONE MAN'S FAMILY: television scripts
    - from 11/4/1949 to 1/27/50 (Volume 1)
    - 2/2/50 4/27/50 (Volume 2)
    - 5/4/50 5/31/50 (Volume 3)
    - 7/29/50 10/21/50 (Volume 4)
    - 10/28/50 1/20/51 (Volume 5)
    - 1/27/51 4/21/51 (Volume 6)
    - 4/28/51 7/21/51 (Volume 7)
    - 9/22/51 12/22/51 (Volume 8)
    - 12/29/51 3/22/52 (Volume 9)
    - 3/29/52 6/21/52 (Volume 10)
  - Subseries C. I LOVE A MYSTERY - Index to the Original Run radio scripts in bound volumes in the Department of Special Collections, Green Library, Stanford University, with explanatory notes and additional broadcast information.
    BOOK & VOL, STORY TITLE, SEQUENCE NUMBER, BROADCAST DATES START & END, EPISODES & NUMBERS, BOOK & VOL
    - --Series starts on NBC Pacific coast, Standard Brands, M-F, 15 min
      - The Roxy Gangsters, 01/16/39 02/03; 1; 15 1-15 (Volume 1 66)
      - Death Aboard the Lady Mary, 02/06/39 02/24; 2; 15 16-30 (Volume 1 66)
      - Case of the Nevada Cougar, 02/27/39 03/31; 3; 25 31-55 (Volume 2 67)
      - Mystery of the Lazy K Ranch, 04/03/39 04/28; 4; 20 56-75 (Volume 3 68)
      - Strange Affair at Sandy Spring Sanitorium {Soda Springs Sanitarium}, 05/01/39 05/19; 5; 15 76-90 (Volume 4 69)
      - The Texas Border Smugglers, 05/22/39 06/09; 6; 15 91-105 (Volume 4 69)
      - The El Paso Texas Murders, 06/12/39 06/30; 7; 15 106-120 (Volume 5 70)
      - Yolo County/Battle of the Century, 09/06/39 09/29; 11; 18 166-183 (Volume 6 74)
    - --Series moves to entire NBC Red Network
      - Blue Phantom, 10/02/39 10/20; 12; 15 184-198 (Volume 6 74)
      - Castle Island, 10/23/39 11/17; 13; 20 199-218 (Volume 7 75)
      - Hollywood Cherry, 11/20/39 12/08; 14; 15 219-233 (Volume 8 76)
      - Bury Your Dead, Arizona, 12/11/39 12/29; 15; 15 234-248 (Volume 8 76)
      - San Diego Murders, 01/01/40 01/19; 16; 15 249-262 (Volume 9 77)
      - Temple of Vampires, 01/22/40 02/16; 17; 20 263-282 (Volume 10 78)
    - --Series re-starts on NBC Red Network, Thursdays, 30 min.
      - The Snake with [the] Diamond Eyes, 04/04/40 06/27; 18; 13 (Volume 11 79)
    - --Series re-starts on NBC Blue Network, Mondays, 30 min.
      - The Tropics Don't Call It Murder {The Tropics Taste Murder}, 09/30/40 12/30; 19; 13 (Volume 12 84)
      - The Case of the Transplanted Castle, 01/06/41 03/03; 20; 9 (Volume 13 85)
      - Murder on February Island, 03/10/41 05/05; 21; 9 (Volume 14 86)
      - Eight Kinds of Murder, 05/12/41 06/30; 22; 8 (Volume 15 89)
      - The Monster in the Mansion, 10/06/41 11/24; 23; 8 (Volume 16 92)
      - Secret Passage to Death, 12/01/41 02/02; 24; 10 (Volume 17 93)
      - Terror of Frozen-Corpse Lodge, 02/09/42 04/04; 25; 9 (Volume 18 94)
      - Pirate Loot of the Island of Skulls, 04/13/42 06/29; 26; 12 (Volume 19 95)
    - --End of NBC series
    - --Series re-starts, CBS, Proctor & Gamble, M-F, 15 min.
      - The Girl in the Gilded Cage, 03/22/43 04/09; 27; 15 1-15 (Volume 20 101)
      - Blood on the Cat, 04/12/43 05/07; 28; 20 16-35 (Volume 21 102)
      - The Killer of the Circle M, 05/10/43 06/04; 29; 20 36-55 (Volume 22 103)
      - Stairway to the Sun {The Island in the Sky}, 06/07/43 07/16; 30; 30 56-85 (Volume 23 104)
      - The Decapitation of Jefferson Monk, 08/30/43 10/01; 33; 25 116-140 (Volume 24 106)
      - My Beloved is a Vampire, 10/04/43 11/05; 34; 25 141-165 (Volume 25 107)
      - The Hermit of San Felipe, Atabapo, 11/08/43 12/03; 35; 20 166-185 (Volume 26 108)
      - The Deadly Sin of Sir Richard Coyle, 12/06/43 12/24; 36; 15 186-200 (Volume 26 108)
      - The Twenty Traitors of Timbuktu, 12/27/43 02/05; 37; 44 201-244 (Volume 27 112)
      - The Widow with the Amputation, 03/27/44 04/21; 39; 20 265-284 (Volume 28 113)
      - I am the Destroyer of Women, 04/24/44 05/12; 40; 15 285-299 (Volume 28 113)
      - You Can't Pin a Murder on Nevada, 05/15/44 06/02; 41; 15 300-314 (Volume 29 114)
      - The Corpse in Compartment C, Car 76, 06/05/44 06/09; 42; 5 315-319 (Volume 30 115)
      - The Thing Wouldn't Die, 06/13/44 07/07; 43; 19 320-338 (Volume 30 115)
      - Bride of the Werewolf, 09/19/44 10/09; 47; 15 390-404 (Volume 30 119)
      - Portrait of a Murderess, 11/10/44 12/07; 49; 20 428-447 (Volume 31 121)
      - Find Elsa Holberg, Dead or Alive, 12/08/44 12/29; 50; 16 448-463 (Volume 31 121)
    - --Series ends, CBS
      NOTES:
      STORY TITLE: Story titles do not appear on the scripts until the beginning of the NBC 30 minute series (the story I have numbered 18). The first 4 stories have no titles in the Stanford script volumes, stories 5-7 have handwritten titles on the volume flyleaves, and stories 11-17 have typed titles on the volume flyleaves. [In the case of story 11, the Yolo County was typed and the Battle of the Century added, handwritten, after it]. Story titles in {braces} are original (or at least earlier) titles.
      SEQUENCE NUMBER: Stories were not numbered in the NBC or CBS series - the numbers are mine according to the sequence as I believe it to be. N.B. - some sequence numbers are omitted. These are stories which were broadcast, but the scripts were allegedly not written by Morse, and are not in the Stanford volumes. For your information, the missing titles (some of these, and their exact order, are uncertain, but are my judgement based on internal or external evidence) are -
      8 Flight to Death
      9 Murder, Hollywood Style
      10 Incident Concerning Death
      31 The Graves of Whamperjaw, Texas
      32 Murder is the Word for it
      38 The African Jungle Mystery
      44 The Case of the Terrified Comedian
      45 The Man Who Hated to Shave
      46 The Temple of Vampires (2nd version)
      48 The Monster in the Mansion (2nd version)
      Some of the missing sequence numbers correspond with missing volume numbers - this may or may not be significant.
      EPISODES & NUMBERS: The first number is the number of episodes in the story, and the next pair, if any, are the actual episode numbers. The episodes in the first 15 minute (NBC) series were numbered sequentially as shown, and again (restarting from 1) for the 15 minute CBS series. None of the 30 minute episodes have episode numbers. There are some discrepancies in correspondence among broadcast dates, numbers of episodes, and episodes numbers, as detailed below.
      BOOK & VOLUME: These come directly from the bound volumes. Note that there are two books numbered 30, but with different volume numbers.
      DISCREPANCIES RESOLVED:
      A There are two different, consecutive episodes in the NBC series both numbered 258 in story 16.
      B There was no episode broadcast 11/4/40, election eve; thus the 13 episodes of story 19 cover 14 weeks.
      C The script for the first episode of story 33 is numbered 114. However, the script numbered 123 is followed (in the story) by one numbered 126, and I assume (from other evidence) a numbering error occurred between episodes 86 and 113 which was later corrected, and that the numbering given above is correct.
      D A numbering error midway through story 36 makes it appear that that story ends with episode 195 and story 37 begins with episode 196, but the error was corrected midway through story 37, and the numbering given above is correct.
      E No episode was broadcast 12/31/43.
      F The next five episodes after 6/12/44 were re-dated - perhaps the program was pre-empted on that date.
      JLW 11/22/92
      [John L. Woodruff
  - Bound Volumes of I LOVE A MYSTERY Radio Scripts
    - a. THE ROXY GANGSTERS, From 1/17/39 to 2/24/39 (Volume 1)
    - b. DEATH ABOARD THE LADY MARY
    - CASE OF THE NEVADA COUGAR, 2/27/39 3/3/39 (Volume 2)
    - MYSTERY OF THE LAZY K RANCH, 4/3/39 4/28/39 (Volume 3)
    - a. STRANGE AFFAIR AT SANDY SPRING SANITORIUM, 5/1/39 6/9/39 (Volume 4)
    - b. THE TEXAS BORDER SMUGGLERS
    - EL PASO MURDERS, 6/12/39 6/30/39 (Volume 5)
    - a. YOLO COUNTY BATTLE OF THE CENTURY, 9/6/39 10/30/38 (Volume 6)
    - b. BLUE PHANTOM
    - CASTLE ISLAND, 10/23/39 11/16/39 (Volume 7)
    - a. HOLLYWOOD CHERRY, 11/20/39 12/28/39 (Volume 8)
    - b. BURY YOUR HEAD, ARIZONA
    - SAN DIEGO MURDERS, 1/1/40 1/19/40 (Volume 9)
    - TEMPLE OF THE VAMPIRES, 1/22/40 2/16/40 (Volume 10)
    - THE SNAKE WITH THE DIAMOND EYE, 4/4/40 6/27/40 (Volume 11)
    - THE TROPICS DON'T CALL IT MURDER, 9/10/40 12/30/40 (Volume 12)
    - THE CASE OF THE TRANSPLANTED CASTLE, 1/6/41 3/3/41 (Volume 13)
    - EIGHT KINDS OF MURDER, 3/10/41 5/5/41 (Volume 14)
    - MURDER ON FEBRUARY ISLAND, 5/12/41 6/30/41 (Volume 15)
    - THE MONSTER IN THE MANSION, 10/6/41 11/24/41 (Volume 16)
    - SACRED PASSAGE TO DEATH, 12/1/41 2/2/42 (Volume 17)
    - TERROR OF FROZEN-CORPSE LODGE, 2/9/42 4/6/42 (Volume 18)
    - PIRATE LOOT OF THE ISLAND OF SKULLS, 4/13/42 6/29/42 (Volume 19)
    - THE GIRL IN THE GILDED CAGE, 3/22/43 4/9/43 (Volume 20)
    - BLOOD ON THE CAT, 4/12/43 5/7/43 (Volume 21)
    - THE KILLER OF THE CIRCLE M, From 5/10/43 to 6/4/43 (Volume 22)
    - STAIRWAY TO THE SUN, 6/7/43 7/16/43 (Volume 23)
    - THE DECAPITATION OF JEFFERSON MONK, 8/30/43 9/30/43 (Volume 24)
    - MY BELOVED IS A VAMPIRE, 10/4/43 11/5/43 (Volume 25)
    - a. THE HERMIT OF SAN FELIPE ATABAPO, 11/8/43 12/23/43 (Volume 26)
    - b. THE DEADY SIN OF SIR RICHARD COYLE
    - THE TWENTY TRAITORS OF TIMBUKTU, 12/27/43 2/25/44 (Volume 27)
    - a. THE WIDOW WITH THE AMPUTATION, 3/37/44 5/12/44 (Volume 28)
    - b. I AM THE DESTROYER OF WOMEN
    - YOU CAN'T PIN A MURDER ON NEVADA, 5/15/44 6/1/44 (Volume 29)
    - BRIDE OF THE WEREWOLF, 6/5/44 7/6/44 (Volume 30, Volume Vol. 119)
    - THE CORPSE IN COMPARTMENT C CAR 76, 9/19/44 10/9/44 (Volume Vol. 115)
    - THE THING WOULDN'T DIE
    - a. PORTRAIT OF A MURDERESS, 11/10/44 12/28/44 (Volume 31)
    - b. FIND ELSA HALBERG DEAD OR ALIVE
  - Bound Volumes of early MYSTERY SERIES Radio Scripts
    - CROSS-EYED PARROT from 5/16/30 to 7/11/30 (Volume 1.)
    - DRAGON IN THE SUN 7/18/30 9/17/30 (Volume 2.)
    - CITY OF THE DEAD 9/26/30 11/28/30 (Volume 3.)
    - CAPT. POST'S CRIME SPECIALIST 12/5/30 to 1/30/31 (Volume 4.)
    - RETURN OF CAPT. POST 4/24/31 6/26/31 (Volume 5.)
    - THE GAME CALLED MURDER 7/4/31 9/4/31 (Volume 6.)
    - DEAD MEN PROWL 10/28/31 12/30/31 (Volume 7.)
    - WITCH OF ENDOR 4/11/32 6/20/32 (Volume 8.)
  - BOUND VOLUME OF POLICE CHIEF QUINN'S STORIES
    - CHINATOWN SQUAD (Volume Vol. 9)
      - 1. KING OF THE GAMBLERS 7/1/32
      - 2. THE GIRL STARTS A TONG WAR 7/6/32
      - 3. INSPECTOR MANION'S COUP 7/22/32
      - 4. CAT AND THE OPIUM DEN 7/29/32
      - 5. LITTLE PETE CHINATOWN'S BIG SHOT 8/5/32
      - 6. THE POET WHO TURNED KILLER 8/12/32
      - 7. IN THE DAYS OF THE HIBINDER 8/19/32
      - 8. NEVER TRUST A MURDERER 8/26/32
      - 9. THE ATRESS AND THE SLAVE GIRL 9/2/32
      - 10. BIG CHINESE JIM'S WHITE WIFE 9/9/32
  - HOUSE OF MYTHS Radio
    - 1929-1930 (Volume Vol. 12, Volume 1)
    - 1930 (Volume 13, Volume 2)
    - 1930 (Volume 14, Volume 3)
  - BOUND VOLUME OF RADIO SCRIPTS
    - ADVENTURES IN LIFE 4/6/1930 (Volume Vol. 15)
      - 1. TWENTY-FOUR HOURS
      - 2. THE CAT HAD KITTENS
      - 3. THE SEVENTH SACRIFICE
      - 4. CARELESSLY SPOKEN
      - 5. THE PHILOSOPHICAL COURTSHIP
      - 6. LIGHT UNTO GODS
  - PIGSKIN ROMANCES 12 episodes 1932 (Box 1, Volume Vol. 16)
  - BOUND VOLUME RCA SPLIT-SECOND TALES
    - June 20, 1930 to Sept. 26, 1931 (Volume 1, Volume Vol. 18)
      - 1. THE RAW FIR DEAL
      - 2. THE CASE BEFORE THE COURT
      - 3. COUNT BOURGET BAD CHECK ARTIST
      - 4. LOVE VIA THE RADIO
      - 5. IT'S A BOY!
      - 6. FOOD FOR THE CHINESE WAR
      - 7. RAW SILK THEN THE DEBT HOLIDAY
      - 8. BUSINESS AND THE GIRL
      - 9. A CRISIS IN THE STOCK MARKET
      - 10. AN ARGENTINE LOVE STORY
      - 11. THE JAPANESE EARTHQUAKE
      - 12. WITH THE ARMED FORCES IN MANILA
      - 13. TWO BABES ON A RADIOGRAM
      - 14. BUSINESS ACROSS THE CONTINENT
      - 15. JAPANESE CANNED CRAB
    - Oct. 10, 1931 - Jan. 16, 1932 (Volume 2, Volume Vol. 19)
      - 1. COLUMBUS UP-TO-DATE
      - 2. ACROSS THE PACIFIC WITH THE GRAF ZEPPELIN
      - 3. BY ELEPHANTS AND RADIO
      - 4. CRISIS - XMAS NUTS
      - 5. BACK STAGE IN A MUSICAL SHOW
      - 6. SHIPS AND SALING ORDERS
      - 7. THANKSGIVING GREETINGS
      - 8. A 100,000 SOLD SHORT
      - 9. LOVE AND PINEAPPLE IN HAWAII
      - 10. BELGIUM CONGO DIAMOND
      - 11. A XMAS STORY
      - 12. NEW YEARS AROUND THE WORLD
      - 13. BUSINESS WITH THE ORIENT
      - 14. A HERO IN NICARAGUA
      - 15. A GEM FOR MILADY
      - 16. HAVANA CIGARETTE GIRL
      - 17. PUTTING BUSINESS ON ITS FEET
  - ADVENTURES IN LIFE 1931Radio
    - ILLUSTRATED TALES 1931 (Volume Vol. 20)
    - SHIPWRECK TALES
    - TWISTED TALES
    - SHORT STORIES
  - BART AND MIKE Radio
    - THE CHINESE TEAR BOTTLE (Volume Vol. 21)
    - THE KILLER AT THE WHEEL 9/6/30-31
  - BOUND VOLUME OF POLICE CHIEF QUINN'S STORIES
    - BARBARY COAST NIGHTS 1/6/33 - 3/10/33 (Volume Vol. 23)
      - 1 SCHOOL FOR PICKPOCKETS
      - 2 SHANGHAI JOHNNY AND THE SOAPBOX PREACHER
      - 3 TIM BORDEN TAKES THE $80,000
      - 4 SPOTTED BILLY, HIGHWAYMAN
      - 5 SALOME JANE OF THE GOLDEN CITY
      - 6 WHEN PRIZEFIGHTS WERE TABOO
      - 7 JIM McDONALD SALOONKEEPER
      - 8 COUNT VON HAMMER AND BICYCLE BANDITS
      - 9 THE PRINCE OF FORGERS
      - 10 THE HUNGRY LION AND THE AFRICAN DODGER
  - JACK AND ETHEL Radio
    - April 9, 1930 (Volume 1, Volume Vol 24)
    - Aug. 6, 1930 (Volume 2, Volume 25)
    - (Volume 3, Volume 26)
    - (Volume 4, Volume 27)
  - ROADS TO HOLLYWOOD Radio
    - Jan. 13, 1931 to March 17, 193115 min. episodes, 20 episodes (Volume 1, Volume Vol. 28)
    - March 24, 1931 to June 30, 1931 (Volume 2, Volume Vol. 29)
  - BABES IN RADIOLAND 1930
    - SLICES OF LIFE (Volume Vol 30)
    - BILLY AND HIS GANG
  - BOUND VOLUME OF POLICE CHIEF QUINN'S STORIES
    - KILLED IN ACTION (Volume Vol. 31)
      - 1 THE MAN FATE KILLED 4/7/33 - 6/9/33
      - 2 HE BEGGED TO BE A POLICEMAN
      - 3 GRAVE ROBBERS AND MURDERERS
      - 4 BROTHER OFFICERS
      - 5 MURDER ON TURK STREET
      - 6 KILLING OF SGT. JOSEPH BRADY
      - 7 SGT. MORIARITY OF THE MIDNIGHT WATCH
      - 8 THE COURAGE OF GEORGE CAMPBELL
      - 9 THE DEATH OF OFFICER WIMMIAM MANNING
      - 10 THE KILLING OF OFFICER MERVYN REARDON
  - 11 half-hour of radio 1930-1932 (Volume Vol. 32)
    - 1. WAR PANTS
    - 2. COMEDY OF ERRORS
    - 3. LITTLE BO PEEP
    - 4. CALIFORNIA GHOST STORY
    - 5. IN THE VALLEY OF THE MOON
    - 6. $500,000 DIAMOND ROBBERY
    - 7. MURDER AMONG FORCE
    - 8. THE CONSTITUTION
    - 9. THE STORY OF ISAAC
    - 10. LOVE STORY OF JACOB
    - 11. THE STORY OF DAVID
  - 1931-32 MORE HOURS ON THE AIR (Volume Vol. 33)
    - 1. SAGA OF BILLY THE KID (adaptation from book)
    - 2. IN THE BEGINNING (Bohemian Grove Play)
    - 3. CIMMARRON (adaptation from motion picture)
    - 4. CASTE (adaptation from play)
    - 5. MURDERS OF THE RUE MORGUE (adaptation from story)
    - 6. THE GOOD OLD DAYS
    - 7. THE WORLD WITH GRACE
    - 8. PASSAGE BY ZEPPELIN
    - 9. SCHOOL DAYS
    - 10. REPUBLICAN CAMPAIGN
  - BOUND VOLUME OF POLICE CHIEF QUINN'S STORIES
    - TO THE BEST OF HIS ABILITY
      - 1 TEMPTATION OF A POLICE INSPECTOR 5/2/34 (Volume Vol. 37)
      - 2 TEMPTATION OF A PATROLMAN 5/9/34
      - 3 THREE CHICAGO MURDERERS 5/16/34
      - 4 TRAFFIC IN NARCOTICS 5/23/34
      - 5 MARY, QUEEN OF THE PICKPOCKETS 5/30/34
      - 6 OFFICER FARLEY, BIG BROTHER 6/6/34
      - 7 THE SOCIETY BANDITS RACKET 6/13/34
      - 8 THE CASE OF MISS MARY LING 6/20/34
      - 9 BAD BILL, DAYLIGHT BANDIT 6/27/34
      - 10 AT HOME WITH A POLICEMAN 7/4/34
  - 10 min. Tales 31 episodes (Volume Vol. 45)
    - SONGS OF LIFE
    - CRAGMONT STORIES
  - 11 episodes March 31, 1935
  - COLLECTED SCRAPS 1934 (Volume Vol. 46)
    - 1. STAGE SKITS
    - 2. STORY OUTLINES
    - 3. FOR PRESS RELEASE
    - 4. AUDITIONS
    - 5. FIRST RADIO EFFORTS
    - 6. FATHERS ARE IMPORTANT
  - SOMETHING OF EVERYTHING 1935-36 (Volume Vol. 53)
    - BOHEMIAN CLUB XMAS PLAY 1935
    - FARCE ON XMAS PLAY (Thursday Night LOW JINX 1936)
    - IN THE BEGINNING OUTLINE FOR GROVE PLAY
    - RETURN OF THE GODS (Specimen copy for radio series)
    - BEHIND THE SCENE WITH KING ARTHUR (Specimen for radio)
    - THIS YOUNGER GENERATION (Spec. for radio)
      - 1. GIRLS OF 15!
      - 2. GIRLS ATTRACTED TO OLDER MEN
    - THE MAN OF THE HOUSE (Spec. copy)
    - ANOTHER CATHY STORY (used on Sunday special
    - THE COP ON THE BEAT (used on Sunday spec)
    - Episode out of the lives of the Barbours (used for screen test)
    - JACK'S FAMILY SCRAPBOOK (copy for Barbour scrapbook)
    - ONE MAN'S FAMILY audition (used to audition girls)
    - PORTRAIT OF ANN SHELLY (used in Radio Guide)
    - INFLUENCE OF OMF on members of cast (used in Radio Mirror)
    - Letters from MJB salesman to his uncle (spec. for air)
    - STUDIO CHATTER (used on the air by Clinton Twiss)
  - Further Scraps (Radio) (Volume Vol. 61)
  - SOME OF EVERYTHING 1938-1940 (Volume Vol. 80)
    - CUSTODIANS OF THE EARTH (Aud. Scripts 1 and 2)
    - THE BOOK CONCERNING THE CARE AND FEEDING OF A RADIO WRITER
    - BURIED AND DUG UP (outline of musical comedy lyrics)
    - BANK OF AMERICA SHOW (audition script)
    - THAT GIRL SANDY (outline for musical comedy)
    - LETTER TO MR. GILMAN CONCERNING OMF DOING ROAD TOUR
    - THIS YOUNGER GENERATION (audition script)
    - BOHEMIAN CLUB Skit AFTERGLOW OF GROVE
    - FAMILY EN ROUTE (audition script)
    - HIGHLIGHTS OF OMF (in outline for Life Picture lay-out)
    - FOR PATRICIA, a poem
    - PRESIDENT'S BIRTHDAY PARTY OMF on Infant Paralysis
    - TREASURE HUNT (outline for ILAM)
    - PROWL IN THE NIGHT (a mystery part)
    - YOU WERE MEANT TO BE A STAR (audition for Dorothy Arzner)
    - YOU WILL BE DEAD IN A MONTH (half-hour episode for ILAM)
  - I LOVE ADVENTURE 1948 (Volume Vol. 114)
    - 1. THE CHINA COAST INCIDENT
    - 2. THE GREAT AIR MAIL ROBBERY
    - 3. THE DEVILS SANCTUARY
    - 4. THE PEARL OF GREAT PRICE
    - 5. THE $100,000 MANHUNT
    - 6. THE FINISHING SCHOOL KIDNAPPING
    - 7. BUT GRANDMA, WHAT BIG TEETH YOU HAVE
    - 8. THE MAN WITH THE THIRD GREEN EYE
    - 9. TEHE GIRL IN THE STREET
    - 10. THE KWANG-MOON DAGGER
    - 11. ASSIGNMENT WITH A DISPLACED PERSON
    - 12. HEARSE ON THE HIGHWAY
    - 13. THE AMBASSADOR RICARDO SANTO INCIDENT
  - WAR REPORTS, ETC. 1942 (Volume Vol 118)
    - PAEN TO DAVID - I AM AN AMERICAN
    - THE AMERICAN SCENE (Manuscript)
    - THE AMERICAN SCENE (script)
    - THE CASE OF ROBERT
    - THE VERY ROOT OF CIVILIZATION
    - THIS MORNING ENGLAND STANDS (novel)
    - THE COMMON MAN
    - WE ARE PROUD
    - NO WALL
    - HUMANITY
    - TO MOULD CHARACTER
    - THE KNOCK ON THE DOOR (U.S. Bond Pledge drive)
    - A CIVILIAN'S TRIBUTE TO ALL MEN IN UNIFORM
    - THE TEMPTATION OF PROF. AND MRS. HEATH
    - THE CHITLING BIRD
    - HAVE YOU HEARD?
    - THE GIRLS ON THE ISLE OF MINDANAO
    - SPECIAL PLUG
    - LETTER TO FELLOW GUILD MEMBERS
    - HOW TO WRITE A 15-MIN. RADIO DRAMA
    - RESUME OF THE AMERICAN SCENE
    - USO MATERIAL (For Barton Yarborough in Texan dialect)
    - USO MATERIAL (For Barton Yarborough in Texan dialect)
    - THE CAT
    - VOLUNTEER RATIONING BOARDS
    - WOMEN IN INDUSTRY
    - PARADE OF THE STARS
    - THIS IS MY STORY (The Am. Red Cross)
    - HOARDING
    - WOMEN IN INDUSTRY
    - THE AMERICAN STORY
  - THE AMERICAN SCENE 1947
    - 1. The American Scene (Bohemia)
    - 2. GUSSIE THE GOOSE GIRL (Bohemia)
    - 3. SO YOU WANT TO STAY MARRIED, (8 episodes)
    - 4. THE POND (1st and 2nd revision)
    - 5. TIMOTHY JOHN, (6 episodes)
    - 6. THE CREEPS (Girl on the Street)